Hi!
There are 2 basic products that you're going to need in order to engage in braiding your hair.
One of them would probably be pomade or a mud.
Depending on the coarseness of your hair and the thickness of your hair, you're going to want to intrude something that's a little heavier.
Fiber based products are a little bit on the heavier side.
Ashley has rather fine hair, so I'm going to use something that's a little bit more lightweight just in order to give myself a little bit more manageability with her hair.
You see how it just kind of tames the frizz and it just kind of smooths her hair down.
That way when I actually am braiding, her hair will fall a little flatter and it will be easier to work with and more manageable.
Another product that you're going to need is some sort of hairspray.
Hairspray you usually find in your light hold, medium hold, and your heavy.
If you were spraying your hair before you do the braid, I definitely recommend using a light hold hairspray.
Anything too heavy is going to set your style before you have your style in.
You want your hair to pliable.
You want to be able to move it.
You want to be able to create that smoothness and do everything you need to, but you want to make it easier on yourself.
Braiding can be a little bit harder with hand coordination because of the movements of the hair.
You only have 2 hands and at times you're holding more than 4 sections of hair.
You do want your hair to still remain soft and pliable, so that way you're not harming what you have already done.
It's not going to make it harder for you to actually use.